Kearney Taaffe 3260 Pablo Cir, Round Rock, TX 78665 | kearney.taaffe@gmail.com | (817) 239-2783

SUMMARY

I'm a software engineer who loves to learn new things and build projects. I've done everything from program a sprinkler system on a Raspberry Pi to building UIs using React and Material UI. I've architected and developed APIs in various languages, deployed web apps to Heroku and AWS, and even built a react native app. I've been doing full stack for the past 7 years, but I'm ready to tackle any challenge.

SKILLS

Languages and Frameworks: TypeScript, NodeJS, React, Vue, PHP, ExpressJS, Prisma, React Native

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, MariaDB, PostgreSQL, MS SQL

Development Tools: Git, Vite, npm

DevOps: FireBase, AWS Route 53, AWS S3, EC2, NginX, Lighttpd,

MariaDB replication

3rd Party: Okta, Stripe, PayPal, JWT, NodeMailer, PUG

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer (Nov 2022 - Dec 2023) Softrams

- Built and application tracking system using VueJS, Postgres, ExpressJS, Prisma ORM
- Integrated Stripe and NodeMailer into an ExpressJS API
- Built a React Native app that integrated with an IdP (Identity Provider) for identity federation between various government domains

Senior Front-End Engineer (Sep 2021 - Oct 2022) Meeting Protocol Worldwide

- Migrated a web app from Symfony 2 to 5
- Tweaked MongoDB schemas to be more performant
- Designed and built a new UI in Bootstrap 5. Integrated it

into Symphony 5

Software Engineer - Contractor (Jan 2021 - August 2021) Visa

- Developed a library of individual ADA compliant components that could be "dropped" into templates
- All components could be used with either mouse or keyboard navigation
- Integrated Redux Sagas and API calls for efficient handling of extremely large datasets

Full Stack Engineer - Contractor (Apr 2020 - Jan 2021) Rodeo Logistics

- Developed a web application to extract, transform, and load scores from a file to a MS SQL API
- Worked on a team to migrate from React class components to function components using useState and useEffect
- Performed code reviews and helped write unit testing in Mocha for both the Node API and the React front-end

Full Stack Developer (Aug 2019 - Feb 2020) Leading Reach

- Successfully maintained a Symfony API by fixing bugs and creating new MySQL stored procedures for customer reports
- Enhanced an Angular web application by fixing bugs, adding new features
- Deployed new releases using Travis for CI
- Performed code reviews; Participated in backlog grooming and breaking of epics

Full Stack Developer - Contractor (Mar 2018 - Aug 2019) MacMillan Learning

- Worked with a small team to develop a cutting edge online learning tool, that allowed for automated grading of homework & tests
- Fixed issues with a MySQL Node API and successfully deployed fixes using Docker and Jenkins
- Utilized BDD & TDD to build highly complex web applications

that were ally compliant

Laravel Developer - Contractor (Oct 2017 - Feb 2018) LegacyBeta

- Worked with client to migrate a Laravel web application to React and Lumen
- Integrated with the QuickBooks API to generate reports on sales, billing, and to generate invoices
- Maintained Linux server with nginx and PHP-FPM and tuned MySQL DB

Full Stack Developer - Contractor (Jan 2017 - Oct 2017) Finance Genius

- Integrated the NADA API into a Codeigniter web app
- Developed a KnockoutJS web app that modified PDF files
- Figured out how to setup all development environments using Docker and xDebug

RaspberryPi Developer - Contractor (Feb 2016 - Jan 2017) Pecan Street Project

- Built an API using CherryPy on a RaspberryPi to control sprinkler systems
- Extended an Angular SPA to display power generation graphs using Vis.JS
- Built a web-scraper using Python and BeautifulSoup to download, unzip, and parse CSV and XLS files from ERCOT

API Developer - Temp (Nov 2015 - Feb 2016) Perk

 Worked with Android game developers to develop an API to keep track of player time, win-loss ratio, and in-game currency

IVR Engineer (May 2014 - Oct 2015)

Krush Communication

- Developed IVR systems using DigiTalk and MS SQL stored procedures
- Fixed issues with Zend 1 framework

 Performed routine maintenance and upgrades of PHP webapp and IVR app

Web Developer II (Aug 2013 - April 2014) Emmis Communications

- Extended and maintained an in-house ticketing system written in Kohana 3.5
- Created new reports using Vis.JS to display metrics of user engagement
- Performed routine maintenance and upgrades of a WordPress site

Software Engineer (Aug 2009 - June 2013) Affinegy

- Created custom branded websites to host software downloads for clients
- Created a TR-69 compliant web server to communicate with routers
- Created TR-69 scripts to issue updates to routers
- Used RightScale to maintain AWS server

Telephony Engineer (Jan 2006 - June 2009) Network IP

- Developed IVR applications that allowed for processing credit card payments
- Developed an API to communicate with PayPal and CyberSource
- Configured Lighttpd servers to run PHP code
- Worked on a team to convert 1.7M lines of Java code to Python & PHP
- Worked on a team to convert a C application to Python

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science University Texas at Arlington - Arlington, TX